Finding Aid for Marston Bates Papers 1913-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Marston Bates Papers 1913-1974
Bates, Marston, 1906-1974.
Professor of zoology at the University of Michigan, scientist for the Rockefeller Foundation, and scientific writer for both professional and popular publications. Correspondence, journals, manuscripts of writings, and class materials, including papers detailing his work with the United Fruit Company in Central America, 1928-1931, his later activities with the International Health Division of the Rockefeller Foundation, especially his interest in mosquito research and malaria control programs during the 1930's and 1940's, and his demographic studies of the people of the Ifalik Atoll in the South Pacific in 1953; and photographs.
851144 Aa 2
25 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Marston Bates (donor no. 5441 ) in 1973.
The collection is open for research.
Marston Bates, scientist and writer, was professor of zoology at the University of Michigan from 1952 until his death in 1974. Prior to that time, Bates worked for the United Fruit Company (1928-1931) in Central America, and later with the Rockefeller Foundation (1935-1952). In addition, he was Sheldon Traveling Fellow from Harvard University to Cuba (1934-1935), special assistant to the president of the Rockefeller Foundation (1950-1952), member of the National Research Council's expedition to the Ifalik Atoll in the South Pacific (1953), director of research at the University of Puerto Rico (1956-1957), member of the Committee on Biological and Medical Sciences of the National Science Foundation (1952-1958), trustee of the Cranbrook Institute of Science (1955-1962),and Phi Beta Kappa visiting scholar (1962-1963 and 1968-1969).
Although distinguished for his research on mosquitoes, malaria, and yellow fever, Bates was perhaps best known, in the words of the New York Times, as a "Nontechnical Naturalist", a man who was able to write readable scientific works.
The Bates papers cover the period 1913-1974 and include material relating to all phases of his career, including his research in Guatemala and Honduras with the United Fruit Company, his studies of mosquito biology and malaria control programs during the 1930's and 1940's in Albania, Egypt, Colombia, and elsewhere and his later investigations into problems of demography and human ecology. The collection includes correspondence, personal and scientific journals, miscellaneous entomological notes, manuscripts of many of his books, articles, and book reviews, copies of the scripts of his television appearances, and University of Michigan class notes. The collections also includes personal photographs and photographs relating to his scientific research.
The collection has been arranged into six series: Correspondence; University of Michigan; Journals, diaries, research; Writings; Notes/miscellaneous personal; and Photographs.
Subjects:
Bates, Marston, 1906-1974.; Central America.; Cranbrook Institute of Science.; Darwin Centennial Celebration (1959: University of Chicago); Ifalik Atoll (Micronesia); Malaria.; Mosquitoes--Control.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division.; United Fruit Company.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Zoology.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; Zoology.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Albania.; Animals.; Bates, Marston, 1906-1974.; Birds.; Central America.; Classrooms--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Colombia.; Ifalik Atoll (Micronesia); Mosquitoes.; Teaching methods.; Television in education.; United Fruit Company.; Zoology.
Contributors:
Abbott, Donald Putnam.; Benítez, Jaime, 1908-2001; Boulding, Kenneth E. (Kenneth Ewart), 1910-1993; Brown, Dugald E. S., 1901-; Bugher, John Clifford, 1901-; Burrows, Edwin G. (Edwin Grant), 1891-1958.; Cain, Stanley A. (Stanley Adair), 1902-1995; Childe, V. Gordon (Vere Gordon), 1892-1957.; Crist, Raymond E.; Darlington, Philip Jackson, 1904-1983.; DeVinney, Leland Collins, 1906-; De Voto, Bernard Augustine, 1897-1955.; Dice, Lee Raymond, 1887-1977.; Douglas, Paul H. (Paul Howard), 1892-1976; Dunn, Emmett Reid, 1894-1956.; Ecological Society of America.; Fairchild, David, 1869-1954.; Fairchild, G. B.; Fairchild, Marian H.; Fleming, R. W. (Robben Wright), 1916-2010.; Gaige, Frederick M.; Gerlach, Lee.; Grosvenor, Gilbert Hovey, 1875-1966.; Grosvenor, Melville Bell, 1901-1982.; Haber, William, 1899-1988.; Hackett, Lewis Wendell, 1884-1962.; Hatcher, Harlan, 1898-1998.; Hicks, Welmer K., 1909-; Hubbell, Theodore Huntington, 1897-1989.; John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation.; Just, Theodor Karl, 1904-1960.; Kennedy, John S.; Kinsey, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles), 1894-1956.; Kumm, Henry William, 1901-; Logan, John A.; Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978.; Muñoz Marín, Luis, 1898-1980.; Pollock, James K. (James Kerr), 1898-1968; Popenoe, Wilson, 1892-1975; Rahn, Sheldon Lloyd, 1918-; Rockefeller, David, 1915-; Rogers, J. Speed (James Speed), 1892-1955; Rusk, Dean, 1909-1994; Russell, Diarmuid.; Sauer, Carl Ortwin, 1889-1975; Sawyer, Ralph A. (Ralph Alanson), 1895-1978.; Scribner, Charles, Jr., 1921-1995; Soop, Everett J., 1901-; Trapido, Harold.; Twente, John W.; Wagman, Frederick H.; Wilgus, A. Curtis (Alva Curtis), 1897-1981.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.; Drawings.
- Correspondence
  The largest series is Correspondence which dates from 1913 to 1970. The early correspondence (1913-1949) is arranged chronologically. The later correspondence (1949-1970) is arranged into five alphabetical subseries. Bates corresponded widely with fellow scientists and his exchanges with them are a rich source of information about research, scientific publication, and professional life.
  - Chronological 1913-1949
    - 1913-1922 (Box 1)
      (1-1)
    - 1923 (Box 1)
      (1-2)
    - January-April 1924 (Box 1)
      (1-3)
    - May-July 1924 (Box 1)
      (1-4)
    - August-December 1924 (Box 1)
      (1-5)
    - 1925 (Box 1)
      (1-6)
    - 1926 (Box 1)
      (1-7)
    - 1927-1928 (Box 1)
      (1-8)
    - January-July 1929 (Box 1)
      (1-9)
    - August-December 1929 (Box 1)
      (1-10)
    - 1930 (Box 1)
      (1-11)
    - January-May 1931 (Box 1)
      (1-12)
    - June-August 1931 (Box 1)
      (l-13)
    - September-October 1931 (Box 1)
      (1-14)
    - November 1931 (Box 1)
      (1-15)
    - December 1931 (Box 1)
      (1-16)
    - January 1932 (Box 1)
      (1-17)
    - February 1932 (Box 1)
      (1-18)
    - March-April 1932 (Box 1)
      (1-19)
    - May 1932 (Box 1)
      (1-20)
    - June 1932 (Box 1)
      (1-21)
    - July-August 1932 (Box 1)
      (1-22)
    - September-October 1932 (Box 1)
      (1-23)
    - November-December 1932 (Box 1)
      (1-24)
    - January 1933 (Box 1)
      (1-25)
    - February 1933 (Box 1)
      (1-26)
    - March 1933 (Box 1)
      (1-27)
    - April-May 1933 (Box 1)
      (1-28)
    - June 1933 (Box 1)
      (1-29)
    - July-August 1933 (Box 1)
      (1-30)
    - September 1933 (Box 1)
      (1-31)
    - October 1933 (Box 1)
      (1-32)
    - November 1933 (Box 1)
      (1-33)
    - December 1933 (Box 1)
      (1-34)
    - January 1934 (Box 1)
      (1-35)
    - February 1934 (Box 1)
      (1-36)
    - March-April 1934 (Box 1)
      (1-37)
    - May 1934 (Box 1)
      (1-38)
    - June 1934 (Box 1)
      (1-39)
    - July-August 1934 (Box 1)
      (1-40)
    - September-October 1934 (Box 1)
      (1-41)
    - November 1934 (Box 1)
      (1-42)
    - December 1934 (Box 1)
      (1-43)
    - January 1935 (Box 2)
      (2-1)
    - February-March 1935 (Box 2)
      (2-2)
    - April-May 1935 (Box 2)
      (2-3)
    - June 1935 (Box 2)
      (2-4)
    - July 1935 (Box 2)
      (2-5)
    - August-September 1935 (Box 2)
      (2-6)
    - October 1935 (Box 2)
      (2-7)
    - November-December 1935 (Box 2)
      (2-8)
    - 1936 (Box 2)
      (2-9)
    - 1937 (Box 2)
      (2-10)
    - 1938 (Box 2)
      (2-11)
    - 1939 (Box 2)
      (2-12)
    - January-July 1940 (Box 2)
      (2-13)
    - August-December 1940 (Box 2)
      (2-14)
    - January-February 1941 (Box 2)
      (2-15)
    - March-April 1941 (Box 2)
      (2-16)
    - May-June 1941 (Box 2)
      (2-17)
    - July-August 1941 (Box 2)
      (2-18)
    - September-October 1941 (Box 2)
      (2-19)
    - November-December 1941 (Box 2)
      (2-20)
    - January 1942 (Box 2)
      (2-21)
    - February-March 1942 (Box 2)
      (2-22)
    - April 1942 (Box 2)
      (2-23)
    - May 1942 (Box 2)
      (2-24)
    - June 1942 (Box 2)
      (2-25)
    - July 1942 (Box 2)
      (2-26)
    - August-September 1942 (Box 2)
      (2-27)
    - October-November 1942 (Box 2)
      (2-28)
    - December 1942 (Box 2)
      (2-29)
    - January 1943 (Box 2)
      (2-30)
    - February 1943 (Box 2)
      (2-31)
    - March 1943 (Box 2)
      (2-32)
    - April 1943 (Box 2)
      (2-33)
    - May 1943 (Box 2)
      (2-34)
    - June 1943 (Box 2)
      (2-35)
    - July 1943 (Box 2)
      (2-36)
    - August 1943 (Box 2)
      (2-37)
    - September 1943 (Box 2)
      (2-38)
    - October 1943 (Box 2)
      (2-39)
    - November 1943 (Box 2)
      (2-40)
    - December 1943 (Box 2)
      (2-41)
    - January-March 1944 (Box 3)
      (3-1)
    - April 1944 (Box 3)
      (3-2)
    - May 1944 (Box 3)
      (3-3)
    - June 1944 (Box 3)
      (3-4)
    - July 1944 (Box 3)
      (3-5)
    - August 1944 (Box 3)
      (3-6)
    - September 1944 (Box 3)
      (3-7)
    - October 1944 (Box 3)
      (3-8)
    - November 1944 (Box 3)
      (3-9)
    - December 1944 (Box 3)
      (3-10)
    - January 1945 (Box 3)
      (3-11)
    - February 1945 (Box 3)
      (3-12)
    - March 1945 (Box 3)
      (3-13)
    - April 1945 (Box 3)
      (3-14)
    - May 1945 (Box 3)
      (3-15)
    - June 1945 (Box 3)
      (3-16)
    - July 1945 (Box 3)
      (3-17)
    - August 1945 (Box 3)
      (3-18)
    - September 1945 (Box 3)
      (3-19)
    - October 1945 (Box 3)
      (3-20)
    - November 1945 (Box 3)
      (3-21)
    - December 1945 (Box 3)
      (3-22)
    - January 1946 (Box 3)
      (3-23)
    - February 1946 (Box 3)
      (3-24)
    - March-April 1946 (Box 3)
      (3-25)
    - May-June 1946 (Box 3)
      (3-26)
    - July-August 1946 (Box 3)
      (3-27)
    - September-October 1946 (Box 3)
      (3-28)
    - November-December 1946 (Box 3)
      (3-29)
    - January 1947 (Box 3)
      (3-30)
    - February 1947 (Box 3)
      (3-31)
    - March 1947 (Box 3)
      (3-32)
    - April-May 1947 (Box 3)
      (3-33)
    - June-July 1947 (Box 3)
      (3-34)
    - August-September 1947 (Box 3)
      (3-35)
    - October 1947 (Box 3)
      (3-36)
    - November 1947 (Box 3)
      (3-37)
    - December 1947 (Box 3)
      (3-38)
    - January 1948 (Box 3)
      (3-39)
    - February 1948 (Box 3)
      (3-40)
    - March 1948 (Box 3)
      (3-41)
    - April 1948 (Box 3)
      (3-42)
    - May 1948 (Box 3)
      (3-43)
    - June 1948 (Box 3)
      (3-44)
    - July 1948 (Box 4)
      (4-1)
    - August 1948 (Box 4)
      (4-2)
    - September 1948 (Box 4)
      (4-3)
    - October 1948 (Box 4)
      (4-4)
    - November-December 1948 (Box 4)
      (4-5)
    - January 1949 (Box 4)
      (4-6)
    - February 1949 (Box 4)
      (4-7)
    - March 1949 (Box 4)
      (4-8)
    - April 1949 (Box 4)
      (4-9)
    - May 1949 (Box 4)
      (4-10)
    - June 1949 (Box 4)
      (4-11)
    - July 1949 (Box 4)
      (4-12)
    - August 1949 (Box 4)
      (4-13)
    - September 1949 (Box 4)
      (4-14)
    - October-November 1949 (Box 4)
      (4-15)
    - December 1949 (Box 4)
      (4-16)
    - Correspondence undated, 1920-1940 (Box 4)
      (4-17)
    - Correspondence undated, 1940-1950 (Box 4)
      (4-18)
    - Income Tax Returns 1948-1954 (Box 4)
      (4-19)
  - Alphabetical 1949-1954
    - A (Box 4)
      (4-20)
    - Activity Reports (Box 4)
      (4-21)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 4)
      (4-22)
    - American Geological Society (Box 4)
      (4-23)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences (Box 4)
      (4-24)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences (Box 4)
      (4-25)
    - The American Naturalist (Box 4)
      (4-26)
    - B (Box 4)
      (4-27)
    - B (Box 4)
      (4-28)
    - Bartholomew, George A (Box 4)
      (4-29)
    - C (Box 4)
      (4-30)
    - Chapman & Hall, Ltd. (Box 4)
      (4-31)
    - Columbia Bicentennial Conference V (Box 4)
      (4-32)
    - D (Box 4)
      (4-33)
    - Diary of Marston Bates, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
      (4-34)
    - Dobzhansky, Th. (Box 4)
      (4-35)
    - E (Box 4)
      (4-36)
    - Expense Accounts & Travel (Box 4)
      (4-37)
    - F (Box 4)
      (4-38)
    - G (Box 5)
      (5-1)
    - Geography, Isaiah Bowman School of (Box 5)
      (5-2)
    - Gollancz, Ltd. (Box 5)
      (5-3)
    - H (Box 5)
      (5-4)
    - Hackett, Lewis W (Box 5)
      (5-5)
    - Hopkins Lectures 1954 (Box 5)
      (5-6)
    - I (Box 5)
      (5-7)
    - J (Box 5)
      (5-8)
    - Journals and Magazines (Box 5)
      (5-9)
    - K (Box 5)
      (5-10)
    - L (Box 5)
      (5-11)
    - M (Box 5)
      (5-12)
    - N (Box 5)
      (5-13)
    - National Research Council (Box 5)
      (5-14)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 5)
      (5-15)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 5)
      (5-16)
    - O (Box 5)
      (5-17)
    - P (Box 5)
      (5-18)
    - Q (Box 5)
      (5-19)
    - R (Box 5)
      (5-20)
    - Research Club-U of M (Box 5)
      (5-21)
    - Rockefeller Foundation-Field (Box 5)
      (5-22)
    - Rockefeller Foundation-New York (Box 5)
      (5-23)
    - Rockefeller Foundation-Projects (Box 5)
      (5-24)
    - Rogers, J. Speed (Box 5)
      (5-25)
    - Russell, Diarmuid (Box 5)
      (5-26)
    - S (Box 5)
      (5-27)
    - Saturday Review of Literature (Box 5)
      (5-28)
    - Scribner's Sons (Box 5)
      (5-29)
    - Societies, memberships (Box 5)
      (5-30)
    - Strode, George K (Box 5)
      (5-31)
    - T (Box 5)
      (5-32)
    - Trapido, Harold (Box 5)
      (5-33)
    - U-V (Box 5)
      (5-34)
    - W (Box 5)
      (5-35)
    - Weir, J.M. (Box 6)
      (6-1)
    - Wenner-Gren Foundation (Box 6)
      (6-2)
    - Wenner-Gren Foundation (Box 6)
      (6-3)
    - XYZ (Box 6)
      (6-4)
  - Correspondence relating to Publications
    - The Natural History of Mosquitoes (Box 6)
      (6-5)
    - The Nature of Natural History (Box 6)
      (6-6)
    - Where Winter Never Comes: A Study of Man...in the Tropics (Box 6)
      (6-7)
  - Alphabetical 1954-1958
    - A (Box 6)
      (6-8)
    - Abbott, Donald (Box 6)
      (6-9)
    - Abbott, Donald (Box 6)
      (6-10)
    - The American Naturalist (Box 6)
      (6-11)
    - The American Scholar (Box 6)
      (6-12)
    - B (Box 6)
      (6-13)
    - B (Box 6)
      (6-14)
    - Biology Textbook-Plans (Box 6)
      (6-15)
    - Burrows, Edwin G (Box 6)
      (6-16)
    - C (Box 6)
      (6-17)
    - Cambridge University Press (Box 6)
      (6-18)
    - Conference in Tropics 1954 (Box 6)
      (6-19)
    - Conservation (Box 6)
      (6-20)
    - Council on Foreign Relations (Box 6)
      (6-21)
    - Cranbrook Institute of Science (Box 6)
      (6-22)
    - D (Box 6)
      (6-23)
    - E (Box 6)
      (6-24)
    - Ecology (Box 6)
      (6-25)
    - Evolution of Behavior, Conference on 1955 (Box 6)
      (6-26)
    - F (Box 7)
      (7-1)
    - G (Box 7)
      (7-2)
    - Guggenheim Foundation (Box 7)
      (7-3)
    - H (Box 7)
      (7-4)
    - Harvard Visiting Committee (Box 7)
      (7-5)
    - I-J (Box 7)
      (7-6)
    - K (Box 7)
      (7-7)
    - L (Box 7)
      (regarding Darwin Centennial in part)
      (7-8)
    - M (Box 7)
      (7-9)
    - Mc (Box 7)
      (7-10)
    - Museum of Comparative Zoology (Harvard) (Box 7)
      (7-11)
    - N (Box 7)
      (7-12)
    - National Book Committee (Box 7)
      (7-13)
    - National Geographic Magazine (Box 7)
      (7-14)
    - National Research Council (Box 7)
      (regarding Cranbrook in part)
      (7-15)
    - National Research Council (Box 7)
      (7-16)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 7)
      (7-17)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 7)
      (7-18)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 7)
      (7-19)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 7)
      (7-20)
    - Negley, Harrison (Box 7)
      (7-21)
    - O (Box 7)
      (7-22)
    - P (Box 7)
      (7-23)
    - Pacific Science Board (NRC) (Box 7)
      (7-24)
    - Prevalence of People (Box 7)
      (7-25)
    - Puerto Rico 1956-1957 (Box 8)
      (8-1)
    - Puerto Rico 1956-1957 (Box 8)
      (8-2)
    - Puerto Rico 1956-1957 (Box 8)
      (8-3)
    - Puerto Rico 1956-1957 (Box 8)
      (8-4)
    - Q (Box 8)
      (8-5)
    - R (Box 8)
      (8-6)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 8)
      (8-7)
    - Russell, Diarmuid (Box 8)
      (8-8)
    - S (Box 8)
      (8-9)
    - Saturday Review (Box 8)
      (8-10)
    - Scientific American (Box 8)
      (8-11)
    - Scriber's (Box 8)
      (8-12)
    - Scriber's (Box 8)
      (8-13)
    - Scriber's (Box 8)
      (8-14)
    - Scriber's-Darwin Reader (Box 8)
      (8-15)
    - Student and Faculty Recommendations (Box 8)
      (8-16)
    - T (Box 8)
      (8-17)
    - Television (Box 8)
      (8-18)
    - U-V (Box 8)
      (8-19)
    - W (Box 8)
      (8-20)
    - Wenner-Gren Foundation--Conference on Man's Role in Changing Earth (Box 8)
      (8-21)
    - Wenner-Gren Foundation--Post Conference (Box 8)
      (8-22)
    - XYZ (Box 8)
      (8-23)
  - Alphabetical 1958-1961
    - A (Box 8)
      (8-24)
    - Abbott, Donald (Box 8)
      (8-25)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 8)
      (8-26)
    - B (Box 9)
      (9-1)
    - Biological Sciences Curriculum Study (Box 9)
      (9-2)
    - Biological Sciences Curriculum Study (Box 9)
      (9-3)
    - C (Box 9)
      (9-4)
    - Chicago Press (Box 9)
      (9-5)
    - Cornwell, George W (Box 9)
      (9-6)
    - Cranbrook Institute of Science (Box 9)
      (9-7)
    - D (Box 9)
      (9-8)
    - Darwin Centennial Convocation (Box 9)
      (9-9)
    - E (Box 9)
      (9-10)
    - Eisley, Loren (Box 9)
      (9-11)
    - Encyclopedia Americana (Box 9)
      (9-12)
    - F (Box 9)
      (9-13)
    - Fan Mail-TV (Box 9)
      (9-14)
    - Florida, University of (Box 9)
      (9-15)
    - Forest & the Sea-Fan mail (Box 9)
      (9-16)
    - G (Box 9)
      (9-17)
    - H-I (Box 9)
      (9-18)
    - J-K (Box 9)
      (9-19)
    - L (Box 9)
      (9-20)
    - M (Box 9)
      (9-21)
    - Martin Bionics Symposium (Box 9)
      (9-22)
    - Michigan Mental Health Institute (Box 9)
      (9-23)
    - Michigan. University Press (Box 9)
      (9-24)
    - Museum Press (Box 9)
      (9-25)
    - N (Box 9)
      (9-26)
    - National Research Council (Box 9)
      (9-27)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 9)
      (9-28)
    - Natural History Magazine (Box 9)
      (9-29)
    - Oklahoma and Arkansas (Box 9)
      (9-30)
    - P (Box 9)
      (9-31)
    - Pacific Science Board (Box 9)
      (9-32)
    - Pacific Science Congress (10th) (Box 9)
      (9-33)
    - Permissions (Box 9)
      (9-34)
    - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 9)
      (9-35)
    - Puerto Rico (Box 9)
      (9-36)
    - Prentice-Hall (Box 10)
      (10-1)
    - Prentice-Hall (Box 10)
      (10-2)
    - R (Box 10)
      (10-3)
    - Random House (Box 10)
      (10-4)
    - Russell, Diarmuid (Box 10)
      (10-5)
    - S (Box 10)
      (10-6)
    - Scribner's Sons (Box 10)
      (10-7)
    - T-U (Box 10)
      (10-8)
    - UNESCO (Box 10)
      (10-9)
    - V-W (Box 10)
      (10-10)
    - Wesleyan University (Box 10)
      (10-11)
  - Alphabetical 1961-1966
    - A (Box 10)
      (10-12)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences (Box 10)
      (10-13)
    - American Library Association (Box 10)
      (10-14)
    - American Scholar (Box 10)
      (10-15)
    - American Society of Naturalists (Box 10)
      (10-16)
    - B (Box 10)
      (10-17)
    - Beacon Press (Box 10)
      (10-18)
    - Biological Abstracts (Box 10)
      (10-19)
    - Biological Sciences Curriculum Study (Box 10)
      (10-20)
    - Bradford Junior College (Box 10)
      (10-21)
    - Bucknell University (Box 10)
      (10-22)
    - C (Box 10)
      (10-23)
    - California, University of (Box 10)
      (10-24)
    - Chanticleer Press (Box 10)
      (10-25)
    - Chanticleer Press (Box 10)
      (10-26)
    - Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station (Box 10)
      (10-27)
    - Conservation Foundation (Box 10)
      (10-28)
    - Council on Foreign Relations (Box 10)
      (10-29)
    - D (Box 11)
      (11-1)
    - E (Box 11)
      (11-2)
    - F (Box 11)
      (11-3)
    - Fan Mail--Coral Island (Box 11)
      (11-4)
    - Fan Mail--Forest & Sea (Box 11)
      (11-5)
    - Fan Mail--Miscellaneous (Box 11)
      (11-6 --11-8)
    - Fort Lauderdale Historical Society (Box 11)
      (11-9)
    - G (Box 11)
      (11-10)
    - Guggenheim Foundation (Box 11)
      (11-11)
    - H (Box 11)
      (11-12)
    - Home Builders (Box 11)
      (11-13)
    - I (Box 11)
      (11-14)
    - J (Box 11)
      (11-15)
    - K (Box 11)
      (11-16)
    - L (Box 11)
      (11-17)
    - Life Magazine Books (Box 11)
      (11-18)
    - M (Box 11)
      (11-19)
    - Mc (Box 11)
      (11-20)
    - Macinko, George (Box 11)
      (11-21)
    - Man & Nature-Fan Mail (Box 11)
      (11-22-11-23)
    - Minnesota (Box 11)
      (11-24)
    - N (Box 11)
      (11-25)
    - National Health Council (Box 11)
      (11-26)
    - National Research Council (Box 11)
      (11-27)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 11)
      (11-28)
    - New York Times (Box 11)
      (11-29)
    - Notre Dame (Box 11)
      (11-30)
    - O (Box 11)
      (11-31)
    - Organizations for Economic Co-operation and Development (Box 11)
      (11-32)
    - P (Box 12)
      (12-1)
    - Pacific Science Board (Box 12)
      (12-2)
    - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 12)
      (12-3)
    - Prentice-Hall Inc. (Box 12)
      (12-4)
    - R (Box 12)
      (12-5)
    - Research & Development (Box 12)
      (12-6)
    - Rhode Island (Box 12)
      (12-7)
    - S (Box 12)
      (12-8)
    - Scribner's (Box 12)
      (12-9)
    - Southern Illinois-University (Box 12)
      (12-10)
    - Stephens College (Box 12)
      (12-11)
    - T-V (Box 12)
      (12-12)
    - W (Box 12)
      (12-13)
    - Weather Modification Article (Box 12)
      (12-14)
    - Wenner-Gren Foundations (Box 12)
      (12-15)
    - World Health Organization (Box 12)
      (12-16)
  - Alphabetical 1966-1970
    - A (Box 12)
      (12-17)
    - AAUW (Box 12)
      (12-18)
    - American Geographical Society (Box 12)
      (12-19)
    - B (Box 12)
      (12-20)
    - Biological Sciences Curriculum Study (Box 12)
      (12-21)
    - C (Box 12)
      (12-22)
    - Commission on Undergraduate Education in the Biological Sciences (CEEBS) (Box 12)
      (12-23)
    - Committee on Resources and Man (CRAM) (Box 12)
      (12-24)
    - CRAM Conferences (Box 12)
      (12-25)
    - "Crackpot" (Box 12)
      (12-26)
    - D (Box 12)
      (12-27)
    - E (Box 12)
      (12-28)
    - Eastern North Carolina Colleges, Association of (Box 12)
      (12-29)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica & Universalis (Box 12)
      (12-30)
    - Environmental Quality, Congressional. Committee on (Box 12)
      (12-31)
    - F (Box 13)
      (13-1)
    - Fan Mail--Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      (13-2)
    - G (Box 13)
      (13-3)
    - Gluttons and Libertines (Box 13)
      (13-4-13-5)
    - Guggenheim Foundation (Box 13)
      (13-6)
    - H (Box 13)
      (13-7)
    - Harper & Row (Box 13)
      (13-8)
    - Horizon (Box 13)
      (13-9)
    - I (Box 13)
      (13-10)
    - J (Box 13)
      (13-11)
    - Japan (Box 13)
      (13-12)
    - K-L (Box 13)
      (13-13)
    - M (Box 13)
      (13-14)
    - Michigan Quarterly Review (Box 13)
      (13-15)
    - N (Box 13)
      (13-16)
    - National Humanities Faculty (Box 13)
      (13-17)